

CONTACT ME AT





<u>www.beautifullycoded.co</u>

in /in/RuthieKWoods



SKILLS

HTML

SASS

Javascript

Node.js

React

React Native

MongoDB

PostreSQL

Bootstrap

Styled Components

Materialize

Git Github

NPM

Project Management
Software Development

Budgeting and Cost Analysis

Enterprise Resource Planning

Staff and User Training

Process Improvement

EDUCATION

Communications Northeastern University Jun 2002 - Jun 2003

RUTHIE WOODS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PERSONAL PROFILE

Lover of tech that touches lives uniquely. Super excited to create and maintain meaningful code. I am a Software Engineer with holistic knowledge of software development and design. I am also experienced in coordinating with stakeholders.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

100 Devs | Oct 2020- present

- Design and develop modern full-stack applications across multiple platforms, conduct day-to-day project coordination, planning and implementation across multiple teams and developers, maintaining dynamic ecosystem using today's best practices
- Create functional and technical application documents
- Maintain a detailed git history for all projects and use Github in a team environment
- Contribute Bootstrap styling Code A-holic open source project-an app aimed to brush up on web development skills

Freelance Web Developer

Feb 2019- present

- Conceptualized creative UX/UI interfaces solutions for client's web presence
- Developed websites using WordPress, Squarespace and Wix
- Maintained web pages by scheduling updated and improving performance

Real Estate Consultant-Realtor®

GLM Realty Group| Feb 2014- present

- IOT Operations Lead, led a team of 17 to deploy modern points of sale software lowering firm revenue loss by 25%
- Migrated technical documentation from local databases to Google Docs resulting in elimination of tech debt
- Developed frontend website for firm that reduced variable cost by 20%, clientele growth by nearly 200% during the pandemic after deployment
- Ensure social media and website content aligns with brand and visual format, collaboratively create content for web, social media, manage calendar and projects
- Oversee property marketing on website (design and maintenance), advertise open houses through social media strategy campaigns and incentives for targeted market

Projects

What's in your picture

• Designed an app using Microsoft Azure Cognitive Services that can detect objects in images thus saving you time and reducing workload.

Tech Used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, EJS

Job Compatibility

Designed an app with ability to determine if you are inspired by your career based on analyzing your psychological
disposition thus leading to company and employee incite. Resulting in ways to target, implement and improve
individual and team moral. Team building and motivational connection produces workplace integrity and
longevity, saving company money in hiring related expenses. Job retention improved by upwards of 89%

Tech Used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, EJS

What's the brand

Designed an app with ability to detect brands with rapid recognition thus saving hours of organization, resulting
in more time to dedicated to brand innovation and scalability. Productivity returning upwards of 65% savings
over projected revenue prior to implementation for various clients and venders

Tech Used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, EJS

Show me your face

Designed an app with ability to use facial recognition, thus improving communications between coworkers,
partners, family and friends having trouble gaging or detecting other parties mood this is the help you need. Great
tool for differently enabled people or people who have trouble detecting non verbal ques. Enable screen reader if
needed.

Tech Used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, EJS

Talk to me 2

• Designed an app with ability to use your voice with speech recognition to translate into one of 15 languages in text format thus solving language barriers and communication issues thus expanding network of new connections family, friends and business networks. Connection impressions expanded upwards 50%

Tech Used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, EJS